Guide to the Nicholas School Master's Projects, 1933-2005 UA.18.01.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- 2004 -- Master's Projects, 3 boxes
  - Strader, Rachel: A Comparison of Groundfish Management on the East and West Coasts of the US, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Supples, Christina Marie: A Paradigm Shift: Rethinking Forest Fire Management in the Intermountain West, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Swanson, Jennifer: Carbon Cycling in the Calhoun Experimental Forest, South Carolina, USA, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Tomioka, Miki: Analysis and Recommendations for Management of Chronic Violators in North Carolina, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Trappe, Carleigh: Marine Protected Areas in North Carolina, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Tribo, Jennifer: A Statistical Modeling Assessment of the National Nutrient Criteria in South San Francisco Bay, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Upgren, Amy: The Development of an Integrated Ecological Assessment of the Headwaters of the Araguaia River, Gois, Brazil, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Urlaub, Ivan K.: Health Risks of and Policy Analysis for Reducing Residential Wood Smoke Emissions, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Weiss, Jessica: Foraging Ecology and Maternal Transmission of Foraging Specializations of Bottlenose Dolphins (Tursiops truncatus), 2004 (Box 14)
  - Whitt, Amy D.: Striving Towards Responsible Viewing: An Evaluation of Dolphin-Watch Ecotour Operations in Clearwater, Florida, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Wu, Christopher: A Statistical Modeling Assessment of the National Nutrient Criteria in the Neuse River Estuary, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Zollett, Erika A.: Preliminary Observation of Depredation by Bottlenose Dolphins on the King Mackerel Troll Fishery in Florida, 2004 (Box 14)
- 2005 -- Master's Projects, 2 boxes
  - Alton, Amy: Environmental Performance Measures for the U.S. Port Sector, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Andeck, Greg: Presidential Executive Orders on the Environment, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Arensman, Elena: Integrating Regional Land Use Planning into Local Open Space Protection, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Barkley, Matthew: A Statistical Modeling Assessment of Western North Carolina Lakes, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Biscoe, Melanie L.: DDT Policy for Malaria Control in Africa: Perceptions, Politics, and Policy, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Bowles, Marshall W.: Fault-related Hydrothermal Breccias from 2240'N on the Mid-Atlantic Ridge, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Brazer, Jr., Eric O.: A Policy-Oriented Ethnography of the Winter Bluefin Tuna Fishery in Beaufort and Morehead City, North Carolina, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Brodnax, Sara: Legislative Policy Development: Setting the Environmental Agenda in North Carolina, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Buback, Steven: Environmental Predictors of Crayfish Distribution, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Caldwell, Linda S.: A Predictive Framework of Designated Use Attainment: An Application of Nutrient Criteria Selection for Florida Lakes, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Carney, W. Michael: Differential Toxicity of Naphthoic Acid Isomers in Medaka (Oryzias latipes) Embryos Using a 96-well Plate Format, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Chang, Cheryl: Integrating Carbon Sequestration into National Forest Management, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Choi, Ga-Young: Sea Turtles and the Caribbean Hotel Industry: The Development of a Best Practices Manual, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Choy, Denise: Planning for Sustainable Tourism in Cuba: A Scenario-Based Approach to the Future, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Cimiluca, Christine M.: Jones Lake State Park and Bushy Lake State Natural Area Informational Booklet and Resource Management Plan, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Cohun, Kelly: Managing the Gladden Spit Marine Reserve: An Analysis of the Whale Shark Dive Tourism Industry in Placencia, Belize, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Cornet, Jacquelyn L.: Marine Mammal and the Effects of Noise: Facts about Acoustic Signals and the Potential Impacts of Human Sound Sources, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Daniels, Sarah L.: Climate Change Monitoring Identification of Climate Sensitive Sites in the Southwest Alaska Network of National Parks, 2005 (Box 14)
  - Dunn, Daniel C.: Social and Physical Factors in the Designation of Marine Protected Areas by the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council, 2005 (Box 15)
  - English, Elizabethann: Turtles, Conservation and Conflict: Using Dispute Resolution Systems in the U.K. Caribbean Overseas Territories, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Estes, Emily S.: Statistical Analysis of Water Quality Criteria and Designated Use Attainment for 125 Finnish Lakes, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Fadely, Karen M.: Tourism Zoning for Parque Nacional Ambor, Boliva, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Feighner, Gordon R.: Modeling Carbon Dioxide Emissions Trading for the New England Region, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Fetherston, Elizabeth H.: Sustainability Certification in Community-Based Fisheries, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Fuge, Dylan: Vacant Land in Durham: An Urban Development Resource?, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Gadwood, Lisa Ann: Development Impacts of a Proposed Interstate on Isolated Wetlands in Horry County, South Carolina, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Geiser, Hillary A.: Spatial Applications of PRZM/EXAMS for Watershed-Based Pesticide Risk Assessments, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Gleason, Allison: Assessment of Kayak Industry Education Needs, Florida Keys National Marine Sanctuary, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Goddard, Kelly L.: Tourism and Community-Based Enterprise Development: A Report from Copan, Honduras, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Goetz, Kimberly T.: Summer Habitat Preference of Beluga Whales (Delphinapterus leucas) in Cook Inlet, Alaska, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Gove, Matt: A Comprehensive National Ocean Policy: America's Next Step?, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Greganti, Mary C.: Saving Venice: Flood Prevention and Coastal Management in a Heritage City, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Hagerty, Meghan A.: Fire Suppression and the Decline of the Western Toad in Glacier National Park, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Hammer, Carolyn: Evaluation of the Use of Life Cycle Assessment in Sustainable US Agriculture, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Harris, Adrienne O.: The Land Use Patterns of the Haw River Watershed and their Effects on Water Quality, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Hunt, Alan R.: Conserving the Agricultural Landscape through Farmers' Markets, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Innes, Wilhelmina S.: Survival Rates of Marine Mammals in Captivity: Temporal Trends and Institutional Analyses, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Jayme, Katrina L.: Adapting the Marine Stewardship Council (MSC) Eco-Labelling Program to Developing Country, Small-Scale Fisheries, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Kang, Aram: Tourism and the Great Smoky Mountains National Park: Perspectives of the Business Community, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Keene, Matt: Toward an Effective System of Marine Protected Areas: The Establishment of a Global Forum, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Kingham, Alexis: An Analysis of Re-enrollment Strategies to Maximize Tree Acreage in the Conservation Reserve Program, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Kirk, Whitney Elizabeth: Hybrids or Hydrogen: Automotive Policy for a New Generation, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Kunert, Kelly: A GIS Approach to Habitat Restoration Site Selection and Prioritization in the New York-New Jersey Harbor Estuary, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Kwok, Rose: Prioritizing Wetland Restoration Sites in the Schuylkill River Watershed, 2005 (Box 15)
  - LaPoint, Jodie: The Loss of Forest Habitat for Lemurs in Ankarafantsika National Park, Western Madagascar, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Lee, Crystal S.: Greenhouse Gas Card: Addressing the Disconnect Between Scientific Research and Public Understanding, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Leitch, Amy Sinclair: Visitor Profile and Analysis of Tourism User Fees for Ambor National Park, Bolivia, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Leiterman, Lindsay A.: A Management Plan for Nesting Sea Turtles on Puerto Rico's Undeveloped Beaches, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Maresh, Jennifer L.: Analysis of North Atlantic Right Whale Swimming Behavior During Bottom Foraging Events to Assess Entanglement Risk, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Marichal, Cassandra: Sea Turtle Education Manual for Cipara, Venezuela, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Maxted, Carson: Benchmarking Laboratory Design: A Case for Right-Sizing, 2005 (Box 15)
  - May, Edward E.: The Viability of Utility Scale Wind Power on the North Carolina Coast, 2005 (Box 15)
  - McCoy, William: Evaluation of Local Emergency Planning Committees (LEPCs) in North Carolina, 2005 (Box 15)
  - McDonald, Teresa: Development of Outdoor Environmental Education at Hillandale Elementary School, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Mihnovets, Alicia Nicole: Assessing Beach Nourishment Impacts on Loggerhead Sea Turtle (Caretta caretta) Reproduction on Bogue Banks Island, North Carolina, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, Charlotte: Public Participation in Environmental Decisionmaking in Cuba, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Moir, Ilana Christiann: Prioritizing Areas for Future Conservation Along the Blue Ridge Parkway, 2005 (Box 15)
  - Park, Ji-Won: Development of a New Pulp Mill Facility in Sumatra, Indonesia: The First Ten Years, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Pearson, Georgia: Predicting the Location of Alabama Black Belt Prairie Patches Using Spatial Analysis Tools, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Peng, John H.: The Clean Air Investment Fund Strategy: Benefits, Uses, and Recommendations, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Reif, Melissa W.: An Adaptive Framework for Identifying Puma Refuge Zones in Colorado, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Roberts, Brian T.: A Macroinvertebrate Survey of Sandy Creek in Durham County and Comparison to Other Triassic Basin Watersheds in North Carolina, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Schnitzer, Andrea: Potential Environmental Implications of the Federal Tobacco Buyout: An Evaluation Methodology, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Schonfeld, Haley R.: Conservation Management Plan for a Riparian Corridor Along the Neuse River: Wayne County, North Carolina, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Schuh, Georgia: Lean Manufacturing: Examining the Relationship between Lean and "Green" in the Furniture Industry, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Seiling, Erin: Incentives and Obstacles to Using Living Shorelines Along Estuarine and Riverine Shorelines in North Carolina, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Siraprapasiri, Poom: Comparing Energy Portfolios Across Countries: Do Prices Matter?, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Smith, Jeff: Identifying Strategic Marine Fisheries Habitat in North Carolina, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Stites, Nicole C.: Non-Traditional Sources of Childhood Lead Exposure in Chicago, IL, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Swails, Katherine Sandmeyer: Patterns of Seal Strandings and Human Interactions in Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Thompson, Silvia Freitas: An Analysis of the Green Building Market for Speculative Commercial Developments, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Travis, Lindsay: Community and Ecological Effects of Exurbanization in Western North Carolina Communities, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Watkins, Julia: Stakeholder Perspectives: A Tool for Creating Ecological Guidelines for Rural Residential Development in the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Weaver, Scott: Evaluation of Fuel Options for Biomass Co-Firing in the Eastern United States, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Weingarden, Sarah L.: Improving Electrification for Remote, Rural Households Using Renewable Energy Technologies: A Navajo Nation Study, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Wicker, Jim G.: Smart Seafood: Sustainable Seafood in Carteret County, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Wildman, Nicholas Lee: Estimates of the Economic Benefits from Two Federal Habitat Incentives Programs, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Wolff, Katherine Lynn: Bacterial Source Identification and Management in Jarrett Bay, NC, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Work, Chet: Comprehensive Bird Monitoring: An Assessment Technique for Effective Land Conservation, 2005 (Box 16)
  - Yamamoto, Shiho: The Effects of Forest Fragmentation on Genetic Variability of Japanese Beech (Fagus crenata): A Case Study in the Kurikoma Mountains of Japan, 2005 (Box 16)
- 2006 -- Master's Projects, 3 boxes
  - 2006 Armstrong-Lyons, 1 boxes (Box 61)
  - 2006 Mackey-Young, 1 boxes (Box 62)
  - 2006 DEL Program Boatwright-Romaine, 1 boxes (Box 63)
- 2007 -- Master's Projects, 2 boxes
  - 2007 Aires-Hardy, 1 boxes (Box 64)
  - 2007 Henry-Smith, 1 boxes (Box 65)